nfb.org 2019-10-03

# Privacy Policy | National Federation of the Blind

The National Federation of the Blind respects your privacy and security. 

## Privacy Policy for Users of NFB.org

No personal information acquired through your use of this website is shared with any third party except as is necessary to fulfill a request for a purchase or donation, or to provide a service you request.

In conformance with Payment Card Industry (PCI) guidelines, user credit card information is not stored in National Federation of the Blind databases or retained on National Federation of the Blind servers. In cases where recurring donations are authorized by a user, industry standard PCI conformant techniques are used to store a “token” that identifies the user to the payment gateway; however, this token limits the transactions the National Federation of the Blind can conduct to those frequencies and amounts previously authorized by the user, and no payment card information is stored in National Federation of the Blind databases or retained on National Federation of the Blind servers.

Payments transacted through the National Federation of the Blind website utilize the PayPal Payflow Pro payment gateway. Please see the [Privacy Policy for PayPal Services](https://www.paypal.com/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full) for additional details about how PayPal protects transaction data.

The National Federation of the Blind uses industry standard Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology to encrypt communications between end-user computers and National Federation of the Blind servers, ensuring that information submitted to the National Federation of the Blind is protected from being read by third parties during the transmission process. National Federation of the Blind web servers and internal computer networks are protected from unauthorized access by utilizing industry standard firewalls and best-practice techniques.

In some cases, the National Federation of the Blind website will request the user’s computer to store a small file known as a cookie. Where used, this cookie is necessary to deliver personalized information and functionality which requires the National Federation of the Blind website to identify an end user. This cookie is solely used for delivering personalized experiences. This file is used for no other purpose.

Access by staff to National Federation of the Blind databases is restricted to staff whose assigned duties require such access. Personal login and passwords are required. Login credentials must be changed on a regular basis and are revoked when duties change and/or termination occurs.

Users of nfb.org may request to review personal (if any) data we may have and may request us to change, correct, update, or delete such data, or may express any concerns about the use of private data by emailing [privacy-policy@nfb.org](mailto:privacy-policy@nfb.org) or mailing us at National Federation of the Blind, Attn: Privacy Policy, 200 East Wells Street, Baltimore, Maryland 21230.

## Privacy Policy for Offline Users

The privacy policy for personal data obtained by the National Federation of the Blind through direct mail programs is as follows: 

The National Federation of the Blind sends mail to individuals through the United States Postal Service (USPS). Such mail describes the problems associated with blindness, suggests actions which individuals can take to help alleviate those problems, and requests donations to help support our work. Responses (including credit card donations) to these mailings are processed by a third party vendor specializing in secure processing of payments received through the USPS.

The National Federation of the Blind requires the third party vendor to provide a SOC1 (Report on Controls at a Service Organization Relevant to User Entities Internal Control over Financial Reporting) prepared in accordance with the American Institute of Certified Public Accountants Statement on Standards for Attestation Engagements (SSAE) No.16 Reporting on Controls at a Service Organization.

The National Federation of the Blind maintains a list of responders to its direct mailings on its own servers. The list contains names, addresses, and contribution information. It does not contain credit card data. We use this list to make future mailings to previous donors.  

Individuals may request to be removed from this list by writing to us at National Federation of the Blind, ATTN: Privacy Notification, 200 E. Wells St., Baltimore, MD 21230. 

We sometimes seek to find new individuals who are interested in helping us to alleviate the problems of blindness by exchanging or “renting” names and addresses of individuals who have responded to our direct mail with other organizations who in turn share the names of responders to their direct mail with us. Individuals who do not wish us to exchange their names and addresses with other organizations may request to be removed from our exchange process by writing to us at the Privacy Notification address given above. If you have other questions or concerns about our privacy policy regarding respondents to our direct mail, please contact us at National Federation of the Blind, Attn: Privacy Policy, 200 East Wells Street, Baltimore, Maryland 21230.

(Revised July 2016)
